Sincearosこちら is free to play all of the games,
Sincearosこちら is free to play all of the games,
the distribution of the fantastic Dug Its
素晴らしいDug Itsの配布
modified
修正された
stone
結石
lecture starts
講義が始まります
We ask Vice President Wang Huijun to host for us
王恵軍副社長に司会をお願いします
clap your hands
手をたたいてください
Thank you for listening to our knowledge quiz
知識クイズをお聞きいただきありがとうございました
We think every knowledge test is very good
どの知識テストも非常に優れていると思います
Today I want to say good night first
今日はまずおやすみを言いたいと思います
so today we are happy
だから今日私たちは幸せです
We invite Professor Zhang Wen
張文教授をお招きします
Our fellows are part of the Academia Sinica
私たちの仲間は中央研究院の一員です
Researcher at the Institute of Biology
生物学研究所の研究員
Come tell us a story about this virus
このウイルスについての話を聞かせてください
he got good grades
彼は良い成績をとった
virus is with you
ウイルスはあなたと一緒です
Maybe it's with us now
もしかしたら今も私たちと一緒にいるかもしれない
But his English is also very good
でも彼の英語もとても上手です
Surfing with the viruses
ウイルスとのサーフィン
I think everyone is quite aware of the virus
ウイルスについては皆さんよくご存知だと思います
what's going on
どうしたの？
But Teacher Zhang Wen is an expert among experts in this field
しかし、張文先生はこの分野の専門家の中の専門家です。
So we are very happy to have this opportunity
ですので、このような機会をいただけてとても嬉しいです
Please come to him and talk us deep forward out of the way
彼のところに来て、邪魔にならないように深く話してください
Come tell us some stories about this virus
このウイルスに関する話を聞かせてください
either knowledge or
知識か、
Teacher Zhang Wen is from the Department of Agrochemicals, National Taiwan University
Zhang Wen 先生は国立台湾大学農薬学科出身です。
When I graduated in 1982
1982年に卒業したとき
Go to the U.S. after graduation
卒業後は渡米
是University of Washington
是ワシントン大学
I Washington University
ワシントン大学
University of Washington in Washington
ワシントンにあるワシントン大学
west america university
西アメリカ大学
Get a Ph.D. in hygiene and immunology
衛生学と免疫学の博士号を取得
Then to Mashenri Public School
その後マシェンリ公立学校へ
go to cancer center
がんセンターに行く
doing postdoctoral research
ポスドク研究を行っている
I saw where he went in 1989
1989年に彼がどこへ行ったのかを見ました
I had already left by then
その時までに私はすでに出発していました
So I didn't overlap with you
だから私はあなたと重ならなかった
After Zhang Wen returned to Taiwan
張文が台湾に帰国した後
in our avatar
私たちのアバターで
I always talk about biochemistry
私はいつも生化学について話します
Excuse me
すみません
That doppelgänger is almost gone
あのドッペルゲンガーはもうすぐ消えます
do research
研究を行う
There have been very outstanding results along the way.
その過程で非常に優れた結果が得られました。
Then I won the outstanding awards from everyone in this country, etc.
そして、この国の皆さんから優秀な賞を受賞するなどしました。
So important is our kind
私たちの種類はとても重要です
Internationally
国際的に
if you want a
欲しいなら
This well-known reader is often invited to such international journals
この著名な読者は、そのような国際ジャーナルによく招待されます
Journal Virology
ジャーナルウイルス学
And the editorial board members of the two journals of Virology
そして Virology 誌の 2 誌の編集委員たち
it's not easy
簡単ではない
So do we warmly welcome our Professor Zhang Wen to talk to us today?
それでは、今日、張文教授に話をしていただくことを心から歓迎しますか?
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, Dean Wang Fu
ありがとう、ディーン・ワン・フー
Goodnight everybody
おやすみ皆さん
I am very glad to have this opportunity to talk to you about the virus today
今日はウイルスについてお話しする機会ができてとてもうれしく思います
In fact, today's topic is called Virus is by your side
実は今日のテーマは「ウイルスはあなたのそばにある」です
this is the wind
これは風です
That topic today is the virus is by your side
今日のテーマは、ウイルスはあなたのそばにあるということです
Well, today’s topic is actually not about all viruses.
さて、今日のトピックは実際にはすべてのウイルスに関するものではありません。
Well, I've been doing virus research for about twenty years.
それから約20年間ウイルスの研究をしてきました。
then my favorite virus
それから私のお気に入りのウイルス
So today I'm going to force you to share with me
だから今日はあなたに強制的に共有してもらいます
that's a pox virus
それは痘瘡ウイルスです
Well, this pox virus is actually no stranger in our history.
実は、この痘瘡ウイルスは私たちの歴史においては珍しいことではありません。
So let's just talk about this virus with a few stories
それでは、このウイルスについていくつかの話をしてみましょう
that has something to do with us
それは私たちに関係があります
so let's talk about
それで話しましょう
Why do I have to say in my title
なぜタイトルで言わなければならないのですか
virus is with you
ウイルスはあなたと一緒です
Well I think basically the concept
まあ、基本的にはコンセプトだと思います
It is because the virus is very small
ウイルスが非常に小さいため
Excuse me
すみません
because the virus is small
ウイルスが小さいので
so when it's next to us
だからそれが私たちの隣にいるとき
Actually we don't know
実際のところは分かりません
The second is to say
2つ目は、こう言うことです
Because of the virus, it actually follows the footsteps
ウイルスのせいで実際に足跡を辿る
so it's always next to us
だからいつも私たちの隣にある
it's not like bacteria
細菌のようなものではありません
Bacteria can replicate without us
細菌は人間がいなくても増殖できる
But the virus is real time
しかし、ウイルスはリアルタイムです
must remember
覚えておかなければなりません
so it's actually wrapping around
実際に巻き付いています
by our side
私たちの側で
the most important one is
最も重要なことは
it's everywhere
それはどこにでもあります
So along with remembering it's actually everywhere
だから、それが実際にはどこにでもあることを思い出してください
So in fact, to avoid such a
したがって、実際には、そのようなことを避けるために、
a virus
ウイルス
next to us
私たちの隣に
almost very difficult
ほとんど非常に難しい
let me make an example
例をあげてみましょう
How about a virus
ウイルスはどうですか
we all know
私たちは皆知っています
The definition of a virus is
ウイルスの定義は、
Able to pass through some filtering instruments
一部の濾過可能な機器を通過可能
If I make an analogy here
ここで例えると
Here is the cowpea virus that we often experiment with
これは私たちがよく実験するササゲウイルスです
is a fighting virus
戦うウイルスです
Its size is only about 350nm
そのサイズはわずか約350nmです
nano is 10 to the negative 9th power
ナノは10のマイナス9乗です
So in fact we can't see it with an optical microscope
つまり、実際には光学顕微鏡では見ることができません
Then you have to use the electron microscope
次に電子顕微鏡を使用する必要があります
magnification optical microscope
拡大光学顕微鏡
About usually 100x to 400x
通常100倍から400倍程度
is invisible
見えない
Usually we have to enter tens of thousands of times
通常は何万回も入力する必要があります
or 50,000 times
または50,000回
so you can start to see the shape
形が見え始めるので
The structure is still very unclear.
構造はまだ非常に不明瞭です。
Often times you have to re-enter
再入力が必要な場合が多い
The so-called diffraction of X-rays
いわゆるX線の回折
or more sophisticated instruments
またはより洗練された機器
You can see the structure on its surface
表面の構造がわかります
so it's actually very, very small
実際にはとてもとても小さいです
The second one is that we have measured
2 つ目は、測定したことです。
Collaborate with Mr. Zhang Hongzheng
張宏正氏との共同研究
measured the mass of the virus
ウイルスの質量を測定した
The quality of the virus
ウイルスの質
a particle
一個particle
If it is a particle, it is probably
粒子であれば、おそらく
it has very little mass
質量が非常に小さい
5 out of 10 minus 15 grams
10 個中 5 個から 15 グラムを引いたもの
If the algorithm is called 5 final grains
アルゴリズムが 5 つの最終グレインと呼ばれる場合
In simple terms
簡単な言葉で
That number might sound like...
この数字は次のように聞こえるかもしれません...
let's talk about it
では、それについて話しましょう
if you just imagine a
想像するだけなら
After playing a spray T
スプレーTをプレイした後
The sprayed mist
噴霧されたミスト
In terms of volume
ボリューム的には
probably a microliter
おそらくマイクロリットル
Let's talk about its volume
そのボリュームについて話しましょう
If its density is 1 then
密度が 1 の場合、
you squirt out
あなたは噴出します
the number of viruses on it
そこに存在するウイルスの数
possibly hundreds of millions
おそらく数億
So in this case
したがって、この場合には
In fact, in our daily life, we often
実際、私たちは日常生活の中で、
Walking without knowing it 24 hours a day
24時間知らずに歩いている
something like this
このようなもの
Of course
もちろん
That scientist likes to tune a book
あの科学者は本を調整するのが好きだ
talking about why we do these studies
なぜこのような研究を行うのかについて話す
It's good to take the opportunity to promote
機会を捉えて宣伝するのは良いことだ
Of course everyone can think of that one
もちろん誰もがそれを思いつくでしょう
is in our life
私たちの生活の中で
Since viruses are everywhere
ウイルスはどこにでもいるので
to our life
私たちの生活に
to our health
私たちの健康に
to our economy
私たちの経済にとって
will definitely have some impact
間違いなく何らかの影響を与えるだろう
that many examples
それほど多くの例
everyone can imagine
誰もが想像できる
Every day when I open the newspaper
毎日新聞を開けると
flu virus
インフルエンザウイルス
or hepatitis virus
肝炎ウイルスとか
These are all imaginable
これらはすべて想像の範囲内です
that for those of us who do the research
それは研究を行う私たちにとっても
when walking into the experiment
実験室に入るとき
Viruses have another layer on us
ウイルスは私たちに別の層を持っています
attraction
アトラクション
That is to say, because of his simplicity
つまり、彼の単純さゆえに、
his small his simple
彼の小さい、彼の単純な
When we study to understand the origin of life
生命の起源を理解するために学ぶとき
When wanting to understand something about the mechanisms that work in our body
私たちの体の仕組みについて知りたいとき
In fact, viruses are a very good biological system to start with.
実際、ウイルスはそもそも非常に優れた生物学的システムです。
Let me use an example
例をあげてみましょう
we all know by now
私たちはもう知っています
composition of life words
人生の言葉の構成
a lot of deoxyribonucleic acid
デオキシリボ核酸が多い
that was in 1960
それは1960年のことでした
This is a Central Dog
これはセントラルドッグです
it's immutable
それは不変です
But in fact the first evidence
しかし実際には最初の証拠は
An extension of this concept is the reverse entry virus
この概念を拡張したのがリバースエントリーウイルスです。
His Geno
他的Geno
That means his genome is not actually a DN
つまり、彼のゲノムは実際には DN ではないということです
We're talking about ribonucleic acid
リボ核酸について話しています
So this is overturned
だからこれはひっくり返る
The idea that DNA is the only genome
DNA が唯一のゲノムであるという考え
That's inside a virus
それはウイルスの中にあります
his genome
彼のゲノム
Here is an example
ここに例があります
The second one said that everyone is very concerned about it now.
2 番目の人は、今、誰もがそれを非常に心配していると言いました。
The treatment of cancer or the origin of cancer
がんまたはがんの起源の治療
In fact, the earliest to know
実は一番早くわかるのは、
when cancer occurs
がんが発生したとき
also caused by a virus
これもウイルスが原因で
body of a muscle
筋肉の体
that produced a gene
それが遺伝子を生み出した
The gene brought in by this virus is called SARC
このウイルスによってもたらされる遺伝子はSARCと呼ばれます
what about this
これはどうですか
it will make the muscle body
筋肉質の体を作ります
generate some meat flow
ミートフローを生成する
So it's from the genes like this
こういう遺伝子から来ているんですね
Everyone is starting to realize
誰もが気づき始めている
original cell regulation of cell division
細胞分裂の細胞本来の制御
may be caused by
によって引き起こされる可能性があります
The real cause of so-called cancer
いわゆるガンの本当の原因
all these are
これらはすべて
some of the creatures we grew up with
私たちが一緒に育った生き物のいくつか
something like a virus
ウイルスのようなもの
Extend some of its principles
その原則の一部を拡張する
draw some of its conclusions
その結論の一部を導き出す
Then you can start applying it to larger
次に、それをより大きなものに適用し始めることができます
some
いくつかの
Inside complex biological systems
複雑な生物学的システムの内部
so this is for us
だからこれは私たちのためのものです
Doing research is actually very, very
研究を行うことは実際には非常に非常に重要です
a property of attraction
吸引力的一個性質
Of course, there is another one mentioned in the middle
もちろん、真ん中にもう一つ記載されています
That is to say, the virus must survive
つまり、ウイルスは生き残らなければなりません
this is it
これだよ
we talk about the selfish gene
私たちは利己的な遺伝子について話します
it's the only law
それが唯一のルールです
it has to survive
それは生き残らなければなりません
so it has a very important
非常に重要なことがあります
very important feature
非常に重要な機能
is that it often mutates
それは頻繁に変異するということです
that everyone thinks
誰もが思っていること
Women are fickle
女性は気まぐれだ
people are fickle
人は気まぐれだ
Children are also fickle
子供も気まぐれです
mom said
お母さんは言いました
My child is the most fickle
うちの子が一番気まぐれです
But the fact is that viruses are very fickle.
しかし実際のところ、ウイルスは非常に気まぐれです。
That's one of the strengths of our research
それが私たちの研究の強みの一つです
Because of its fickleness and its adaptation and its evolution
その気まぐれさと適応と進化のために
There is an inseparable relationship between
両者の間には切っても切り離せない関係がある
study its changes
その変化を研究する
Help us understand what is called survival
サバイバルとは何かを理解するのを手伝ってください
So these are the times to study viruses
今こそウイルスを研究するときです
very interesting for some reasons
いくつかの理由で非常に興味深い
In the end, of course
結局のところ、もちろん
if we can understand it
私たちがそれを理解できれば
If you know yourself and your enemy
自分と敵を知っていれば
Of course we can apply it in reverse
もちろん逆に適用することもできます
That can be said in different fields
それはいろんな分野でも言えることだけど
to find a way to use it
それを使う方法を見つけるために
and then do what we want it to do
そして、私たちがやりたいことをやります
That's because there are many types of viruses
ウイルスの種類が多いからね
I just said Wang Fuwen
私は今、王福文と言ったところです
Are there 100,000 or 200,000 types of viruses?
ウイルスの種類は10万、20万あるのでしょうか？
then i just
それから私はちょうど
I don't know how many tens of thousands of viruses there are
ウイルスが何万個あるのか分からない
But basically we can imagine what we just mentioned, that is,
しかし基本的には、今述べたことを想像することができます。
Whether it has 50,000 or 100,000 species
5万種であろうと10万種であろうと
just mentioned that is to say
先ほど言いました、つまり
it has to change
それは変わらなければなりません
if it starts with five
5から始まるなら
It creeps more and it creeps less
より多くクリープし、より少なくクリープします
But the point is that it has to keep changing
しかし重要なのは、変化し続けなければならないということです
Then break through to get a new balance
その後、新たなバランスを得るために突破します
Then the virus we are mainly talking about today
それでは、今日私たちが主に話しているウイルスについて
It's actually Douban
実はドゥーバンです
This may not be a virus that you often hear
よく聞くウイルスではないかもしれませんが、
It may be less talked about in newspapers and magazines
新聞や雑誌ではあまり取り上げられないかもしれません
Then if we look at the classification of viruses
次にウイルスの分類を見てみると
Generally we will divide by his genetic makeup
一般に、彼の遺伝子構成で割ります。
This is a basic
これは基本です
That is, if he is
つまり、彼がそうであれば、
ribonucleic acid as his genetic makeup
彼の遺伝子構造としてのリボ核酸
the way words are copied
言葉がコピーされる方法
Let's call him RNA virus
彼をRNAウイルスと呼びましょう
If he uses deoxyribonucleic acid
デオキシリボ核酸を使用する場合
as his genetic makeup
彼の遺伝子構造として
Let's call him a DNA virus
彼を DNA ウイルスと呼びましょう
Then everyone in Taiwan often hears that
台湾では誰もがよく聞く話です。
Viruses, kids have diarrhea
ウイルスのせいで子供たちは下痢をしている
or flaviviruses like dengue virus
またはデング熱ウイルスのようなフラビウイルス
retroviruses like HIV
HIVのようなレトロウイルス
Ebola virus, he is a very virulent
エボラウイルス、彼は非常に毒性が強い
or flu virus
インフルエンザウイルスとか
Whether it's love flu
恋のインフルエンザかどうか
or human influenza virus
またはヒトのインフルエンザウイルス
These are all RNA viruses
これらはすべてRNAウイルスです
Then their mutations are actually faster in general
その場合、それらの突然変異は実際には一般に高速になります
Then the virus we are going to talk about today
さて、今日お話しするウイルスについて
Actually a DNA virus
実はDNAウイルス
What about DNA viruses?
DNAウイルスについてはどうですか？
it's easier for you to hear
そのほうが聞きやすいです
e.g. herpes virus
例：ヘルペスウイルス
That mouth sometimes breaks
その口は時々壊れます
that is
あれは
He also uses deoxyribose to diagnose viruses
彼はウイルスの診断にもデオキシリボースを使用しています
nucleic acid as his genome
彼のゲノムとしての核酸
What about the pox virus we are talking about today?
今日私たちが話しているポックスウイルスについてはどうでしょうか？
right in this corner
この隅にある
He also uses DNA
彼はDNAも使っている
Then he is in this corner because now
それから彼はこの隅にいる、なぜなら今だから
He probably knew that ten or fifteen years ago
彼はおそらく10年か15年前にそれを知っていたでしょう
he is
彼は
We can always say he is the biggest virus
彼が最大のウイルスであると常に言えます
Now there is an amoeba-infected
今、アメーバに感染した人がいる
mimi virus
ミミウイルス
that becomes the biggest virus
それが最大のウイルスになる
so he is the second most virus
だから彼は2番目にウイルスが多い
ok, then this reflects
OK、これは反映されています
Its size is large because of its complexity
複雑なためサイズが大きくなります
And after he is in the middle of the evolution process
そして彼が進化の過程の途中にあるとき、
It will talk to these small viruses of another Spectrum
それは別のスペクトルのこれらの小さなウイルスと会話します
Strategy that may be used on evolution
進化時に使用できる戦略
that
それか
not the same
同じではありません
Then we will discuss a few today
それから今日はいくつか議論します
It is more related to our human society
それは私たちの人間社会にもっと関係しています
One is the smallpox virus
一つは天然痘ウイルス
The general virus is divided according to his records
彼の記録によれば、一般的なウイルスは分類されている
what about our pox virus
私たちの痘ウイルスはどうですか
If he is infected with vertebrate
脊椎動物に感染している場合
right here
ここにあります
If it's an insect infestation, it goes here.
虫の侵入ならここに行きます。
What are we talking about today?
今日は何について話しますか?
it's all here
すべてここにあります
the first is to look at the other
1つ目は他のものを見ることです
Smallpox virus inside history
天然痘ウイルスの歴史の中
Although the smallpox virus is currently
現在、天然痘ウイルスは存在していますが、
out of human society
人間社会の外へ
we are in society
私たちは社会の中にいます
In fact, there is no such thing as smallpox virus anymore.
実際、天然痘ウイルスなどというものはもう存在しません。
spread in the human world
人間界に蔓延る
But in history
しかし歴史の中では
It is probably the most vicious virus
おそらく最も凶悪なウイルスです
From a historical point of view
歴史的な観点から見ると
It's actually a very old disease
実はとても古い病気なんです
its history presumably goes back
その歴史はおそらく遡る
1200 BC
紀元前1200年
that there is no direct evidence
直接的な証拠がないということ
looking at indirect evidence
間接的な証拠を見ている
The most important piece of evidence
最も重要な証拠
That is to say, in ancient Egypt
つまり、古代エジプトでは
This Pharaoh Ramus V
このファラオ・ラムス５世
On the face of his mummies
ミイラの顔に
in fact here
実はここで
some like
好きな人もいる
acne scar marks
ニキビ跡の跡
and places like these
そしてこのような場所
That's actually a scientist who tried to
それは実際に試みた科学者です
want to be able to get from the top of these skins
これらのスキンの上からアクセスできるようにしたい
Try to see if you can separate
別れられるか試してみる
genes of some viruses
いくつかのウイルスの遺伝子
but so far
しかし、これまでのところ
Haven't heard any positive news yet
まだ明るいニュースは聞いていない
what they separated
彼らが分けたもの
It's still normal
まだ普通だよ
uninfected skin
感染していない皮膚
So the current technology is of course hoping to find
したがって、現在のテクノロジーはもちろん、
more direct evidence
より直接的な証拠
But with a symptom like his
しかし、彼のような症状があると、
can almost be deduced to say
ほぼ次のように推測できる
around 1200 AD
西暦1200年頃
in human society
人間社会では
There are already traces of the smallpox virus
天然痘ウイルスの痕跡はすでに存在する
what about the other one
もう一つはどうですか
There is also no direct evidence
直接的な証拠も無いし
However, according to historians
しかし、歴史家によると、
At this time of 4400 BC
紀元前4400年のこの頃
Athens vs Sparta
アテネ vs スパルタ
that often
それは頻繁に
War is a so-called
戦争というのはいわゆる
A hotbed of activities like Pluck and Virus
Pluck や Virus などのアクティビティの温床
Although we just mentioned
先ほども触れましたが、
Viruses often like to mutate
ウイルスはしばしば変異を好みます
and then be able to adapt to his life
そして彼の人生に適応できるようになる
But in the middle of the process
しかしその過程の途中で
Human beings are absolutely pushing and blocking
人間は絶対に押して阻止する
because once the war
かつて戦争があったから
whole living conditions
生活環境全体
man's permanence
人間の永続性
Then what about living conditions
では、生活環境はどうでしょうか
Hygienic conditions have all declined.
衛生状態はすべて悪化しました。
So that's basically a hotbed of spread.
つまり、それは基本的に拡散の温床です。
So in this historian's record, when
この歴史家の記録によれば、
they will often refer to
彼らはよく言及します
human body, especially limbs
人体、特に手足
there will be some erythema
多少の紅斑はあるでしょう
Then what
じゃあ何
they have a fever
彼らは熱を持っています
the whole thing is
すべては
Most obvious in smallpox is its
天然痘で最も明白なのは、
The farther away from the mid-birth zone
中出生帯から遠ざかるほど
it's whole will be more
それは全体がもっと多くなるだろう
Those like these are basically some descriptions above
このようなものは基本的に上記の説明の一部です
let everyone deduce that
みんなにそれを推理してもらいましょう
In fact to the vid
実際にビデオに
four hundred years ago
四百年前
Smallpox has already begun to spread in Europe
天然痘はすでにヨーロッパで蔓延し始めている
In fact, China also has the so-called
実際、中国にもいわゆる
this smallpox record
この天然痘の記録
That's probably around this B.C.
それはおそらく紀元前あたりのことです。
more than three hundred years ago
300年以上前
that time
その時
because he thought he came in from the outside
外から入ってきたと思ったから
So it's called Lu Chuang
だからルー・チュアンって言うんだよ
Then what
じゃあ何
he had one of the earliest
彼は最も古いものを持っていました
A process on a written record
書面による記録上のプロセス
When Ge Hong entered the court
ゲホンが法廷に入ったとき
he often writes
彼はよく書きます
He wrote many books about medicine
彼は医学に関する多くの本を書きました
you speak now
あなたは今話します
He's probably a pretty good epidemiologist.
彼はおそらくかなり優れた疫学者です。
or an epidemiologist
または疫学者
Because he didn't just record
彼は単に録音しただけではないので、
This possible smallpox situation
この天然痘の可能性のある状況
He actually recorded
彼は実際に録音した
Like rabies or an immediate hoof stab
狂犬病や蹄刺しのようなもの
some other infectious diseases
他の感染症
Some conditions that develop in patients
患者に発症するいくつかの症状
According to the interpretation of ordinary people, this book
この本は一般人の解釈によれば、
kind of like a
のようなもの
I wear this on my hand after I leave
外出後はこれを手に着けます
Then a first aid manual looks a bit like this
応急処置マニュアルはこんな感じです
There are some words in it
その中にいくつかの言葉が入っています
what about these words
この言葉はどうでしょうか
Basically, it is similar to smallpox in modern times
基本的には現代の天然痘に似ています。
Development looks relevant
開発は関連性があるように見える
He said he had a sore and his face was in a hurry
彼は傷ができて顔が急いでいると言った
because it is systemic
それは全身的なものだから
Xu Yu Zhou Zha
シュ・ユウ・チョウ・ジャ
it's all over
すべて終わった
Strong as a fire window
防火窓のように強い
Because it actually has some redness
実際は少し赤みがあるので
Then in the white chapter there will be
そして白の章では、
melt this liquid
この液体を溶かす
Take it with you
持って行ってください
As long as it breaks, it will fall apart again
壊れたらまた壊れる
If not cured, those who refuse will die
治らなければ拒否する者は死ぬ
So the death rate is actually very high
つまり死亡率は実際には非常に高いのです
That
それか
Don't talk about today we say we are in China
今日のことは話さないでください、私たちは中国にいると言っています
In fact, when in Europe
実際、ヨーロッパにいると
or
また
in America
アメリカでは
This smallpox was actually
この天然痘は実は
It is a very serious social disease
非常に深刻な社会病です
We mentioned that in more than 100 AD
西暦 100 年以上のことについては触れましたが、
In fact, a very famous man named Antony Pluck
実際、アントニー・プラックという名前の非常に有名な男は、
That's the fact that we're back again
それが私たちが再び戻ってきたという事実です
this is the roman empire at war
ここは戦争中のローマ帝国です
What about the time of war?
戦争の時はどうでしょうか？
Of course it's a waste of time
もちろん時間の無駄だよ
So what about the people in the city?
では、都会の人たちはどうなのでしょうか？
Because it's hard to count that number
その数を数えるのは難しいので
But history books record about 30% of the population
しかし歴史書には人口の約30％が記録されている
In fact all rose because of smallpox
実際、天然痘のせいで全員が上昇しました
then in this situation
それならこの状況で
In fact, the Roman Empire has no way to survive
実際、ローマ帝国は生き残る方法がありません
his power
彼の力
You can see that it is said in history
歴史上そう言われているのがわかります
In fact, only disease does not distinguish between rich and poor
実際、病気だけが金持ちと貧乏人を区別しない
I colleagues
私は同僚です
So there is no distinction between Chinese and foreign in history
つまり歴史上中国人と外国人の区別はない
In fact, there are quite a few of these palace nobles and even kings
実際、これらの宮殿貴族や王さえもかなりの数います。
He actually had some symptoms of smallpox when he died
実際、彼は亡くなった時、天然痘の症状があった。
Then of course in this case
それから、もちろんこの場合も
There is no such thing as the burial etiquette of the royal family.
王室の埋葬作法などというものは存在しない。
Then all the common people and their relatives
それから、すべての庶民とその親族は、
and inheritance
そして継承
The sons of the throne are practically shunned
王位の息子たちは事実上敬遠されている
That was a lot of times
それは何度もあったよ
Their historians have documented such a process
彼らの歴史家はそのようなプロセスを文書化しています
So you can see that is
つまり、それがわかります
at that moment
その瞬間に
In fact, the toxicity of this disease has nothing to do with its dissemination
実際、この病気の毒性はその蔓延とは何の関係もありません。
In fact, it is already in everyday life
実はすでに日常生活に浸透している
must encounter
遭遇しなければならない
So even if
たとえ
It can also be seen in the literature
文献でも見られます
a record like this
このような記録
in this record
この記録の中で
The traces of smallpox on a girl's face
少女の顔に天然痘の跡
written down and quoted
書き留めて引用する
puppy on black flower
黒い花の上の子犬
So this smallpox
それでこの天然痘は
with a horror shot
ホラーショットで
Level Terrors at the Fair
フェアでの恐怖をレベルアップ
to this beautiful girl
この美しい女の子に
scary look at it like this
怖いよこうやって見て
or give her some threatening scares
または彼女に脅迫的な恐怖を与える
Rifle every use for grace
ライフルは恩寵のために使う
In these young and elegant bodies
この若くて優雅な肉体に
attack
攻撃
left the remand of a face
顔の残骸を残した
so left some marks on the face
それで顔に跡が残ってしまった
So in fact no matter in the medical record
したがって、実際には医療記録には関係ありません
Or in fact, the textual research on the literature
あるいは実際、文献のテキスト研究
can see the ceiling
天井が見える
In fact, many records have been left in human society.
実際、人間社会には多くの記録が残されています。
That day the flowers arrived in America is actually a
あの日アメリカに届いた花は実は
It's actually quite a feeling that this
これは実際にかなりの感触です
this very sad story
このとても悲しい話
because when we are infected
なぜなら私たちが感染したとき
There is a concept that
という概念があります
If today a whole group
今日ならグループ全員で
It doesn't have any herd immunity of its own
それ自体には集団免疫がありません
It has never seen a virus like this
このようなウイルスはこれまで見たことがありません
or when a bacterium
または細菌の場合
Once you have a full-scale invasion
本格的な侵攻が始まったら
In fact, there is no resistance at all
実際には全く抵抗がありません
when in america
アメリカにいるとき
In fact, this is the case
実際、これは事実です
Because when European immigrants entered from Spain
なぜならヨーロッパからの移民がスペインから入ってきたからです。
When entering from Central and South America
中南米から入国する場合
met the indians of south america
南米のインディアンに出会った
Of course it's because the culture is different
文化が違うから当然だけど
Many times they will initially
多くの場合、彼らは最初は
would be in awe of these Spanish immigrants
これらのスペイン移民には畏敬の念を抱くだろう
then later
じゃあ後で
There will be conflicts and wars
紛争や戦争も起こるだろう
Among the immigrants brought
連れてこられた移民の中には
someone has smallpox
誰かが天然痘にかかっています
So it was passed on to the local aborigines
それで地元の先住民に受け継がれたのです
So in fact at that time
それで実はその時は
two major empires
二大帝国
Azac and the so-called Inkars
アザックといわゆるインカール
The two South American cultures
2つの南米文化
In fact within a few decades
実際には数十年以内に
In fact, because of the invasion of smallpox
実は天然痘の侵入により、
disappears soon
すぐに消えます
Then smallpox's footprint goes from South America and up
その後、天然痘の足跡は南アメリカからさらに上へと広がっていきます
that went to north america again
それはまた北アメリカへ行った
When it entered North America
北米に入ったとき
British immigrants, of course, took smallpox
イギリス移民は当然天然痘に罹った
Brought to the New World
新しい世界へ連れて行かれた
When taking to the New World
新世界へ旅立つとき
Indigenous Indians actually have
先住民インディアンは実際に
once allied with the armies of france
かつてはフランス軍と同盟を結んでいた
hope to drive the british away
イギリス人を追い払いたい
The result is in the middle of the process
結果は途中です
England has a general
イングランドには将軍がいる
Called Jeffrey Amist
ジェフリー・アミストと呼ばれる
he moved one
彼は一つ移動した
a bad thought
悪い考え
he thought
彼は思った
I can't win the battle today
今日の戦いには勝てない
I can't convince these aborigines to cooperate with me
この先住民たちに私に協力するよう説得することはできません
Then their extravagance
それから彼らの贅沢
what should I do
私は何をすべきか
So he conspired with several people
それで彼は数人の人々と共謀した
These are all documented
これらはすべて文書化されています
in fact they
実際、彼らは
very famous is
有名なのは
They sprinkled the smallpox virus on this
彼らはこれに天然痘ウイルスを撒いた
straight up
まっすぐに
then sent to the aborigines
その後、先住民に送られました
That aborigines got this
あの原住民がこれを手に入れた
So in fact the entire Tribe is here
つまり、実際には部族全体がここにいます
was greatly affected
大きな影響を受けた
So this is probably our human history
これはおそらく私たち人類の歴史です
You can see the first very malicious exploit of smallpox
天然痘の非常に悪意のある最初の悪用を見ることができます
as a so-called biochemical record
いわゆる生化学的記録として
that threat
その脅威
Of course it is very small in terms of the current perspective
もちろん、現在の視点から見ると非常に小さいです
But we came back to say that
でも僕らは戻ってきてこう言いました
if you today
もし今日あなたが
In a group, there is no resistance at all
集団では全く抵抗がない
History like this is very likely to repeat itself
このような歴史は繰り返される可能性が非常に高い
Then come another history of human beings
そして、人類の新たな歴史が始まる
have such serious influence
それほど深刻な影響を及ぼしている
how is it contagious
どのように伝染しますか
is it possible
出来ますか
To avoid such an infection or to prevent
このような感染症を回避または予防するには
When it was contagious, we just mentioned
伝染性のときは先ほどお話しましたが、
because of his
彼のせいで
his
他的
E-roll is his sneeze
Eロールは彼のくしゃみです
In fact, it can be dispersed in the air
実は空気中にも飛散するんです
It is also recorded in the history that
ということも歴史に記されています
In fact, in the hospital environment
実際、病院の環境では
Just like SARS at that time
あの時のSARSみたいに
In fact, they do have a hospital
実は病院もあるんですよ
Some evidence of cluster infection
クラスター感染のいくつかの証拠
The most common is actually the so-called
最も一般的なのは、実際にはいわゆる
easy contact
簡単な連絡
family
家族
Then or touch him
それから、あるいは彼に触れてください
These things that appear when you are sick
病気のときに現れるこれらのこと
these homes
これらの家
or infected clothing
または感染した衣類
When people like this are actually exposed to infection
こういう人が実際に感染すると
often there will be
多くの場合、あるでしょう
doesn't seem to have much to say today
今日はあまり言うことがないようだ
smallpox depends on food
天然痘は食べ物に依存する
by eating or drinking
食べたり飲んだりすることで
It seems that there is no such direct evidence
そういった直接的な証拠はないようです
Generally speaking, what we just mentioned
一般的に言えば、今述べたことは、
way of infection
感染経路
Then there's another thing, it's actually the virus.
それは別のことです、それは実際にはウイルスです
A very important feature is the
非常に重要な機能は、
he can't help
彼は助けることができない
leaning on insects
虫に寄りかかる
Or run with other animals
または他の動物と一緒に走ったり
So this point is that we humans can exterminate smallpox
つまり、私たち人間は天然痘を撲滅できるということです
a very very very important reason
とてもとてもとても重要な理由
That is to say, today it is trapped in this
つまり、今日はこれに囚われています。
In this ancestor worship environment
この先祖崇拝の環境の中で
If today it can run elsewhere
今日、他の場所で実行できれば
other animals
他の動物
Then wait until the future to jump back into human society
そして未来を待って再び人間社会に飛び込む
Then it will be very difficult for you to exterminate such a virus
そうなると、そのようなウイルスを根絶するのは非常に困難になります
so it is so far no
だから今のところノーだ
Didn't know it could use insect bites
虫刺されにも使えるとは知りませんでした
or springtails or other animals to deliver
またはトビムシやその他の動物を配達する
This is a limitation of the smallpox virus
これは天然痘ウイルスの限界です
Then its influence on that disease
それからその病気への影響
In fact, smallpox is because of the current molecular biology
実際、天然痘は現在の分子生物学のせいです
very developed
非常に発達した
So many times in the early days in the hospital
入院初期には何度も
Some virus strains in the hospital will be isolated
病院内の一部のウイルス株は分離される
people now
現在人就
take it all out
すべてを取り出して
Then he reordered the
それから彼は再注文しました
find a way to get some of this
これを入手する方法を見つける
These viruses in the previous hospital
以前の病院で発生したこれらのウイルス
all sequenced
すべて順序付けられた
Then you can see their comparison
そうすれば、それらの比較を見ることができます
Then basically we can put
それから基本的には置くことができます
Smallpox is divided into two categories
天然痘は 2 つのカテゴリーに分類されます
more serious category
より深刻なカテゴリー
its english name is
その英語名は
Smallpox
天然痘
If those ten people are probably infected
もしその10人が感染している可能性があるとしたら
three to four people will die
3人か4人死ぬだろう
So the death rate is about 30% to 40%.
つまり、死亡率は約30％から40％になります。
The other category is called Verola Minor
もう 1 つのカテゴリーはヴェロラ マイナーと呼ばれます。
Its death rate is lower
その死亡率は低いです
about 1%
約1%
So in fact, in many diseased plants, when
実際、多くの病気の植物では、
while on the internet
インターネット上にいる間
Most of them are actually the sequence of Verola Major
それらのほとんどは実際にはヴェロラ・メジャーのシーケンスです
Then many scientists will be in these sequences
そうすれば、多くの科学者がこれらのシーケンスに参加するでしょう
to find some possible clues
考えられるいくつかの手がかりを見つけるために
Sorry, there will be a few more later
申し訳ありませんが、後でもう少しあります
Although everyone just had dinner
みんなは夕食を食べたばかりなのに
may be a little uncomfortable
少し不快かもしれません
That's basically what we walked through very quickly
基本的にはこれが私たちが非常に早く進めたことです
make you feel
あなたに感じさせる
This is actually a human disease
実はこれは人間の病気なのです
Then when you saw the course of these illnesses
それから、これらの病気の経過を見たとき、
Actually you will understand this
実はこれなら分かるだろう
this virus is fast
このウイルスは速い
It goes on fast in our body
それは私たちの体の中で急速に進行します
probably terrible
おそらくひどい
That means today
つまり今日は
its what we call
それは私たちが呼んでいるものです
this incubation period
この潜伏期間
Its disease is divided into several levels
その病気はいくつかのレベルに分かれています
What about the incubation period?
潜伏期間についてはどうですか？
Actually, you can't see anything sick about it.
実際、それについては何も問題がありません。
The second one is about to get sick.
二人目は病気になりかけています。
May have some symptoms
何らかの症状がある可能性があります
But the skin is still
でも肌はそのまま
not so obvious
それほど明白ではない
And most importantly of course
そしてもちろん最も重要なことは
It has a variety of this blob itself
このブロブ自体にはさまざまな種類があります
in the middle of this process
このプロセスの途中で
Because of its shape it is divided into different stages
その形状により、いくつかの段階に分かれています
What about these stages?
これらの段階についてはどうでしょうか?
go the whole way the whole way
ずっとずっと行く
about two to three weeks
約2〜3週間
Then there is one more thing in the middle of this process
このプロセスの途中でもう 1 つあります。
What scientists have discovered is that
科学者たちが発見したことは、
The incubation period we just talked about
先ほど話した潜伏期間
about seven to ten days
約7日から10日
during this time
この間
The patient is not infectious
患者は感染症ではない
That is to say, during this time
つまり、この間、
actually it goes everywhere
実際にはどこにでも行きます
The chances of it infecting others are actually not very good.
他の人に感染する可能性は実際にはそれほど高くありません。
That's the same as the influenza virus
インフルエンザウイルスと同じだよ
Or other viruses are very different
あるいは他のウイルスは大きく異なります
Many times it is like the tuberculosis we talked about
多くの場合、それは私たちが話した結核のようなものです
it sometimes has no needles
針がない場合もあります
Then this person may actually be infected.
そうすると、この人は実際に感染している可能性があります。
He is when he goes around
彼は歩き回るときもいる
you do not know
あなたは知らない
Then he will infect more people
そうすればもっと多くの人に感染させるだろう
But smallpox is the other way around
しかし天然痘はその逆です
When he didn't have this sick needle
この病気の針がなかった頃
In fact, his infectious power is high
実は感染力が高い
Then I knew he started to have a fever
それから私は彼が熱を出し始めたことに気づきました
Then these homes on the surface
そして、地上の家々は
Start with some flat pillows
まずは平らな枕から始めましょう
then to the raised pillow
それから高さのある枕へ
Then go inside and start having
それから中に入り、食べ始めます
fluid inflamed fluid
液体 炎症を起こした液体
Hua Nong
華農
After the last dry
最後の乾燥後
Run away from home
家出
in the middle of the process
プロセスの途中で
his contagiousness
彼の伝染力
the experiments they did
彼らが行った実験
probably look at that
おそらくそれを見てください
When these organizations
これらの組織が
You can see the yellow line telling you
黄色の線が表示されます。
really contagious
本当に伝染する
Usually it's his surface that's already showing up
通常、すでに現れているのは彼の表面です
Then you can imagine that
そうすれば想像できるでしょう
If a person is walking down the street
人が道を歩いていたら
when he was covered with scars
彼が傷だらけだったとき
everyone will stay away from him
誰もが彼から遠ざかるだろう
So this spread of the virus
それで今回のウイルスの蔓延は
Actually it's not a good thing
実はそれは良いことではない
Well, of course you can also imagine
まあ、もちろん想像することもできます
Later, when the United Nations, everyone in the world
その後、国連が設立されると、世界中の誰もが
when trying to eradicate smallpox
天然痘を撲滅しようとしたとき
To observe patients with smallpox
天然痘患者を観察するため
This is also a very important condition
これも非常に重要な条件です
That is to say
つまり
That is to say, these medical staff
つまり、この医療従事者たちは、
In fact, they can quickly see that
実際、彼らはすぐにそれを知ることができます
who might start to be contagious
誰が感染し始める可能性があるか
then you can go
それなら行ってもいいよ
Go to the main character's contact with other people
主人公と他の人々との接触に行く
This is the time to help him limit his walks
散歩を制限するのを手伝ってあげる時期です
a very important condition
非常に重要な条件
The other one is to wait for him, of course, to get to know the house.
もう 1 つは、もちろん、彼が家に慣れるのを待つことです。
In fact, these homes are actually contagious.
実際、これらの家は実際に伝染します。
Then we just mentioned that
それから、先ほども言いましたが、
He is divided into several types
彼はいくつかのタイプに分けられる
The death rate we are talking about is relatively high
私たちが話している死亡率は比較的高いです
Called Veirola Major
ベイロラ少佐と呼ばれる
Then he has one we call
それから彼は私たちが呼ぶ人を持っています
The most common is called Odinary Type
最も一般的なのは通常タイプと呼ばれます
a lot of it is on the flying nose
その多くは飛んでいる鼻の上にあります
Actually in Europe
実はヨーロッパでは
Also when this smallpox entered Europe
この天然痘がヨーロッパに入ったときも
When Northern Europe and Western Europe
これが北欧や西ヨーロッパだと
many times
何度も
You'll see his mortality inside when
そのとき彼の死が目に見えるだろう
A very high percentage are children
非常に高い割合が子供です
Then of course we can guess
それならもちろん推測できます
That is to say, the development of children's immunity
つまり、子供の免疫力の発達です。
actually weaker than adults
実は大人より弱い
what about the other
もう一方はどうですか
In fact, relatively rare
実は比較的珍しいのですが、
I think you often read it in textbooks
教科書でよく読むと思います
The relatively rare one is actually called Flat type
比較的珍しいものは実際にはフラットタイプと呼ばれます
It doesn't actually have what we just mentioned
実際には、先ほど述べたものは含まれていません
ginger or strong
生姜または濃い
Well it's actually a rash all over
実は全身に発疹があるのです
very thick
非常的厚
And then this patient
そして、この患者さんは
In fact it's a very serious kind of
実際、それは非常に深刻な種類のものです
form of smallpox
天然痘の形態
Because the patient is actually in a coma
患者は実際に昏睡状態にあるため、
then in fact
それから実際には
It's not like this
こんなんじゃないよ
able to respond
対応できる
the third one is scarier
3番目のほうが怖い
It's called Hemorrhage
それを出血といいます
Hemorrhage is
出血というのは、
just bleeding
ただ出血しているだけ
bleeding disorder
出血症
that is, it bleeds under the skin
つまり皮下出血になります
or systemic hemorrhage
または全身出血
some phenomena
いくつかの現象
Generally speaking
一般的に言えば
The meaning of this may be that it
この意味するところは、もしかしたら、
In addition to the spread of the virus
ウイルスの蔓延に加えて、
Possibly some immune-inflammation
おそらく何らかの免疫炎症
some other role
他の役割
in progress
進行中
That's because it's a person's background
それはその人の背景だから
And because in fact this
そして、実際これは
These smallpox are actually a stunt now
これらの天然痘は現在では実際にはスタントです
So we actually
それで私たちは実際に
Looking back on such a dangerous disease
危険な病気を振り返る
In fact, we don't know much about
実際、私たちはそれについてあまり知りません
because of its danger
その危険性のため
So it caused a distance for us to study it
だからそれを研究するのに距離ができてしまった
So in fact, even today
だから実は今日でも
It currently does not exist in human society
現在人間社会には存在しない
But we have a lot of serious pathology like this
しかし、私たちにはこのような深刻な病理がたくさんあります
In fact, its nature is still unclear.
実際、その性質はまだ不明です。
that just mentioned
それは今言った
This is some of them from CGC
これは CGC からの一部です
Some clinical diagnoses
いくつかの臨床診断
They will find that just mentioned
彼らは今言及したことを見つけるでしょう
Once the current situation of bleeding occurs,
現在の出血状況が発生すると、
Almost 100% will die
ほぼ100％死ぬ
If it was the spleen diagnosis just mentioned
先ほど述べた脾臓の診断であれば
It also has a particularly high mortality rate
死亡率も特に高い
The rest is about 30% to 50%
残りは30％～50％くらい
It's the Virula Major we're talking about
私たちが話しているのはウイルスラメジャーです
Of course, if today you have had acne before
もちろん、以前にニキビがあったことがある場合は、
Then your symptoms will be slightly relieved
そうすれば症状も少しは楽になりますよ
That
それか
Of course you don't need to talk
もちろん話す必要はありません
It is said that smallpox will actually have some sequelae
天然痘は実は後遺症があると言われています
i remember when i was little
小さい頃のことを覚えています
In fact, Taiwan also has smallpox
実は台湾にも天然痘があります
because my mother is a friend
お母さんが友達だから
She actually had smallpox when she was little
実は彼女は幼い頃に天然痘に罹っていた
Those who stay can often see
泊まってる人はよく見るよ
There are scars on the face
顔に傷跡がある
So these are actually right
したがって、これらは実際には正しいです
common people's social
庶民の社会
In fact, it has a very large impact
実はそれが与える影響は非常に大きいのです
But for those who do epidemiology
しかし疫学をやっている人にとっては
This is actually what they said in the trace
これは実際に彼らがトレースで言ったことです
the disease in this village
この村の病気
or this disease in this city
あるいはこの街のこの病気
or how long the disease has developed in this place
またはこの場所で病気が発症してからどれくらい経ったか
Then if you want to contain them
それから、それらを封じ込めたい場合は、
They are actually some data
実際にはデータです
with some research directions
いくつかの研究の方向性とともに
In other words
言い換えると
There is another side effect
別の副作用もあります
That is because his infections are often systemic
それは彼の感染症が全身性であることが多いためです
So there will be some people
だから何人かいるだろう
Although the disease is cured
病気が治ってから
His cornea
彼の角膜
In fact, after being affected, there is blindness
実際に罹患すると失明することもある
or limbs
または手足
Because of some of the inflammation we just mentioned
先ほど述べた炎症のせいで
or some festering condition
または何らかの化膿状態
Will have some physical effects
何らかの物理的影響があるだろう
some disabilities
いくつかの障害
Then there are often times in the clinic
それからクリニックではよくあります
It is often said that smallpox often
天然痘がよくあるとよく言われます。
we fight virus
私たちはウイルスと戦います
Sometimes with my colleagues or
時には同僚と一緒に、あるいは
when chatting
チャットするとき
they will say
彼らは言うだろう
Is Zhang Wenshuidou also fighting viruses?
張文水堂もウイルスと闘っているのか？
Then I want to say solemnly
そこで厳かに言いたいのですが、
Water beans are not fighting virus
水豆はウイルスと闘わない
Mizumame
水豆
I don't know why he is called Shui Dou in Chinese
なぜ中国語で水斗と呼ばれるのか分かりません
Probably more water
おそらく水の量が増えると思います
That English is called chicken pops
その英語はチキンポップスと呼ばれています
You just turn it over and it's chickpeas
ひっくり返すだけでひよこ豆になります
Then he actually belongs to the
それから彼は実際に所属しています
He is also a DNA virus
彼も DNA ウイルスです
But he is a herpes virus
しかし、彼はヘルペスウイルスです
So that's a noticeable difference
それは顕著な違いです
Of course beans are different
もちろん豆も違います
These are also distributed differently
これらも配布方法が異なります
These have clinical differences
これらには臨床的な違いがあります
that's right
それは正しい
If we divide this virus into categories
このウイルスをいくつかのカテゴリーに分類すると
The smallpox virus we just mentioned
先ほど触れた天然痘ウイルス
He is usually on the patient
彼は通常、患者の側にいる
It is unlikely that there will be some medical history of so-called previous infection
いわゆる過去の感染症の病歴がある可能性は低い
Because usually the first time
いつもは初めてなので、
it's serious and you can see it
それは深刻です、そしてあなたはそれを見ることができます
But when it comes to chickenpox, these shingle pillow viruses
しかし、水痘の場合は、この帯状の枕ウイルスが
Usually we get chicken pox when we are very young
通常、私たちは幼い頃に水痘にかかります
And what about this virus?
そして、このウイルスはどうなるのでしょうか？
after posting
投稿後
it goes to the ganglia in your body
それはあなたの体の神経節に行きます
it hibernates there
そこで冬眠する
Then our body immunity actually suppresses it
そうすれば、私たちの体の免疫力が実際にそれを抑制します
so it stays inside the original cell
したがって、元のセル内に留まります
no harm to us
私たちに害はありません
but peaceful coexistence
でも平和共存
Then wait until you stay up late to study
それから夜更かしして勉強するまで待ってください
get ready for the forest
森への準備をする
then what
じゃあ何
Meishuibao
美水宝
When your immune system goes down
免疫力が低下すると
it comes up
それは出てくる
Therefore, when many children come to the exam
そのため、多くの子どもたちが試験に来るときは、
Just a lot of holes in the mouth
口に穴がたくさんあるだけ
what about this
これはどうですか
wait until you are immune
免疫ができるまで待つ
and temporarily clear it
そして一時的にクリアします
it's back to that lurking place
あの隠れた場所に戻ってきた
So these different viruses
つまり、これらのさまざまなウイルス
It may represent the same
同じものを表しているのかもしれません
but it is actually
しかしそれは実際には
are two completely different ones
2つはまったく異なるものです
The words here are actually true for some if
ここでの言葉は実際に当てはまる人もいます。
If there is someone who is more interested
もっと興味のある人がいたら
Their mental retardation can be compared
彼らの精神薄弱は比較できる
That is to say, smallpox is actually long
つまり、天然痘は実際には長いのです